Barry: My name is Barry Allen
and I am the fastest man alive.
When I was a child, I saw my mother killed
by something impossible.
My father went to prison for her murder.
Then an accident
made me the impossible.
To the outside world,
I'm an ordinary forensic scientist...
But secretly, I use my speed to
fight crime and find others like me.
And one day, I'll find who killed my mother
and get justice for my father.
I am the flash.
Narrator:
Previously on the flash:
Iris:
The man in the yellow, he took Eddie.
Hi, Barry. Or should I say the flash?
Observe, Barry marries Iris...
And not you.
- I've been having dreams.
- What happens?
Cisco:
Dr. Wells is the reverse-flash...
And he kills me.
If this is Dr. Wells, then who
have we been working for this whole time?
Barry:
A completely different person.
Caitlin: Oh, my god.
I don't wanna kill you, Barry. I need you.
We will face each other again.
Very soon.
Wells:
I want you to take a moment...
And think about all the things
that define your life.
All the people you love.
Your job...
Your coworkers...
Your home.
And now imagine if, one day, in a flash...
All of that vanished.
Would you simply accept your new life
and continue on...
Or would you do whatever it takes...
To get back what was taken from you?
Because I can assure you...
I will get everything that was taken...
From me.
- Hey.
What's all this?
Return labels for Eddie and me.
I ordered 200 to start,
but this afternoon, 2000 arrived.
I guess I ordered wrong.
I have so many now.
Iris, we're gonna find Eddie.
How?
You've searched everywhere.
More than once.
And you haven't found anything.
I'm sorry. I'm not mad at you.
It's just...
You miss him, right?
Yeah, I do.
Wells took my mom from me.
I won't let him take someone from you too.
[Cell phone buzzing]
It's Cisco. I gotta go.
Yeah, go.
Cisco: I kept asking myself...
Why would Wells pretend
to need a wheelchair?
- Sympathy.
- That's what I thought at first.
He's the man in yellow, the reverse-flash.
He's much smarter than that.
Sympathy can't be the only reason.
Misdirect.
Like everything else Wells has done.
I mean, the last person we'd suspect
to be the man in yellow...
- Is someone who lost the use of their legs.
- Exactly right, Joe.
Which is why I started messing around
with the wheelchair.
And that's when I found this.
Damn. You can't get that at radioshack.
Barry:
It looks like the tech inside Gideon.
I measured the output, and this
thing is kicking off serious juice.
I mean, we're talking enough
to power all of central city.
- Joe: Seriously?
- Oh, yeah.
What do you think Wells was using it for?
I think this thing is some kind of battery.
- Battery?
- As in Wells was using it to power himself.
To gain more speed.
And that's why he's so
much faster than you.
[Computer beeping]
The accelerator, it's been reactivated.
- It can't be.
- How is that possible? It blew up.
It had to have been rebuilt.
Even if he did rebuild it, how did
Dr. Wells turn the particle accelerator on?
He's here.
That's why we couldn't find him. He's
been inside s.T.A.R. Labs the whole time.
Stay here.
Cisco, what'd you bring
that orange soda for?
Whenever something happens with the
reverse-flash, liquid floats in the air.
You know, Barry's fish tank...
Wells's champagne...
Lance's coffee. Remember that?
If this does the same thing,
we'll know that Wells is in there.
Do it.
This is big.
Oh, god.
Guys.
Joe: Barry!
Whoa, whoa, whoa. What do we do now?
[Door opens]
Co m p ute r:
Prisoner release protocol initiated.
Oh, no, no, no.
[All grunt]
Peekaboo.
Do you have any idea what it's like
to be stuck in that box?
Now you're the one
who's gonna go into a box.
In the ground.
[Grunts]
[Barry yelling]
- Are you okay?
- Yeah, I will be...
Thanks to Iris.
I'm glad you showed up.
How do you think she got out of there?
- Wells must have released her.
- Eddie: Help!
Wait a sec. Did you hear that?
I checked all the containment cells.
Everyone's accounted for.
No, no. Listen.
Eddie: Help!
Down here!
Help.
[Eddie coughs]
Joe: Eddie?
Oh, partner.
Oh, my god. I got you.
Oh, my god. Eddie.
- You okay?
- Let's get him out of here.
Come on.
There you go. Go slow.
Go slow.
Your vitals are normal,
but you're just a little dehydrated.
The iv should help with that, but
drink some fluids and stay off your feet.
- Okay, Eddie?
- Thanks, Caitlin.
Wells got away.
Ahh. He was too fast.
He's always too fast.
- Eddie.
- We found him under that hatch in the pipeline.
I'm so sorry.
I thought I looked everywhere for you.
It's not your fault.
Sometimes you just can't see the clues...
Even if they're right in front of you.
Um, well, you know, all that's
important is that we're all safe...
And back together, right?
Eddie, why'd he take you?
I don't know.
He said that we're family.
Said his real name is Eobard Thawne.
Eobard Thawne. It's just like in my dream.
Did he say anything else?
I mean, anything that could help us
figure out what he's really after?
He didn't say much.
Just kept working on some tube.
A tube? What did it look like?
Metallic and futuristic.
He said it was the key...
To him getting back
everything that was taken from him.
The key? I don't understand. What...?
I don't know. Look, I just wanna go home.
- Is that okay?
- Caitlin: Yes. Of course.
Iris:
I'll make sure he gets some rest.
Okay.
What do you think Wells was talking about?
I mean...
[Computer beeping]
-Oh, no, no, no. Barry: What?
What now?
Um, are you seeing this?
That's the tube Eddie was talking about.
It's some sort of power source.
That's what's charging up the accelerator.
Can you shut it down?
Do you see a power button
anywhere on this thing?
Dude, this thing is from the future.
It's beyond me.
[Press or touch or cut the wrong thing...
I could bring the building down.
Okay, how long until it's fully functional?
Best I can tell, 36 hours.
That's when Wells will be back.
Why would Wells want
the particle accelerator to work again?
I don't know. It's not like it
was a success the first time.
- It made me the flash.
- That's not all it did.
Caitlin: So, what happens
if the particle accelerator turns on...
While the metahumans are in containment?
They're toast.
We put them there. Now their
lives are in danger because of us.
Look, I think you all know I've never been
a fan of this arrangement here.
I thought the whole plan
was to rehabilitate them and set them free.
It was. We've been a little busy.
Well, if they stay in there, they die. And
if we let them go, they destroy the city.
- We're gonna have to move them.
- Move them where?
- Iron heights can't handle metahumans.
- You're right.
But lian yu can.
What the hell's a lian yu?
Lian yu's the island where Oliver
was stranded for five years.
A.r.g.u.s. Built a
covert military prison on it.
It's where we sent captain boomerang.
Oliver keeps his worst criminals there.
They won't be able to escape.
More importantly, they won't hurt anybody.
So we ship them
from one illegal black site to another.
Yeah, I guess so. Yes.
How do we move them
to Oliver's own private Alcatraz?
I'll call him. Maybe he can help.
And, Cisco, if we do this,
nobody can get loose.
I might have a way
of getting them out safely.
All right, get on it.
Bar, this is insane.
Joe, we have to do this.
You don't think that if we start bussing
supervillains through downtown...
Nobody's gonna notice?
Oh, they'll notice.
That's where you'll come in.
Cecile.
Aw. Mwah. How's my favorite da?
- Thanks for stopping by.
- Hey, anything for my favorite detective.
Hey. So, what can I do for you?
You sounded a little cryptic on the phone.
Yeah, I wanted your opinion on something.
These people with powers?
The metahumans?
Is that what they're calling them?
People love their labels.
Yeah. So let's say, hypothetically,
I know a prison, of sorts.
A place that can do
what iron heights can't...
Where these metahumans, the bad ones...
Are being locked up.
I'd be very concerned.
Especially if, hypothetically,
you had anything to do with it.
Why are you asking me about this?
Well, because Singh's on his honeymoon...
And you're the only other person
I can trust to know this.
Okay, what are you asking me to do?
I need to clear a route through the city.
- Barricades, police cars. The works.
- What am I to tell people? President's in town?
- I don't know. You think they'll believe you?
- No, Joe. They wouldn't.
What you're doing, it's called unlawful
imprisonment and human smuggling.
Joe, those are very bad things.
These are some bad people, cecile.
But their lives are in danger.
I can't. I can't get involved in this, Joe.
I can't.
And as your friend, and possibly the attorney
who will one day be prosecuting you...
I am telling you,
get as far away from this as possible.
Okay, so a.R.G.U.S. Has a transport plane
that can take the metahumans to lian yu.
- We need to get them to Ferris airfield.
- Oliver queen came through.
No, actually. It was not him.
Apparently he's in nanda parbat.
- What?
- Wherever that is. I don't know.
I called Lyla, diggle's wife.
She's gonna hook us up.
So, what about c.C.P.D.
Giving us an escort?
Man, it ain't happening.
You saw me talking to the da.
She was very clear.
I could lose my badge. I could go to jail.
We could go to jail.
We are protecting people.
We are, Barry, but I'm a cop. There's
a certain set of rules I need to follow.
And this year, I broke all of them.
Lying to my boss...
- I know.
- Ignoring the law.
At what point do we become no different
than the people we're fighting?
- We are way different.
- How?
We only break the rules to help people.
Snart: Give me another one.
Ice cold.
Well, well, well.
If it isn't the Scarlet speedster.
You want anything? Beer? Food?
Pickled eggs here are fantastic.
No, I'm good.
I need your help with a problem.
Must be pretty desperate to come
asking for my assistance, but I'll bite.
What do you need?
Help transporting
some people out of the city.
How many?
Five.
Five very bad, very angry people...
Who have powers.
Powers, hmm?
So you want me to, what,
freeze the problem?
Protect you from them
if anything goes wrong?
First rule of business,
always protect yourself.
I'm not gonna help
Usher your enemies out of town.
They're not just my enemies.
They're yours too.
They will destroy central city.
It's not my problem.
You said you love it
here. That this is home.
I do, and it is.
Well, guess what.
These people get loose,
there won't be a city to love anymore.
You won't be able to Rob anyone
if everybody's dead.
It's a compelling argument.
If I'm gonna help you out...
I'll need something in return.
- Like what?
- This.
[Scoffs]
No. This is impossible. I can't do that.
- Then I can't help you.
- There has to...
Snart, there has to be something you want
that I can get.
Let me think about it.
[On jukebox]
You're as cold as ice, I know
you're as cold as ice
Iris: Eddie.
- Hey.
- Where have you been?
Here, work.
You were kidnapped for two weeks, and
your first thought is to go back to work?
I just needed something
constant in my life.
I thought that was us.
Eddie, I miss you.
I love you. Hey.
I saw this when we found you.
This was for me, wasn't it?
When you took me to the waterfront...
And Dr. Wells abducted you,
you were going to propose.
I was.
But now you're not?
What did he do to you?
He didn't do anything to me, Iris.
It's what he showed me.
What could he have shown you
that would make you change your mind?
The future.
He showed me the future, Iris.
We don't get married.
You and Barry do.
I gotta go.
Are you out of your mind? What do you mean
you talked to Leonard snart?
I asked him for help.
Why would you do something so stupid?
Because, Joe,
we have already tried everyone else.
Look, you tried the c.C.P.D. I tried
Oliver. I even tried Ronnie and Dr. Stein.
- The particle accelerator goes online in...
- Sixteen hours.
16 hours, Joe.
I'm not willing to let the metas die,
and we can't let them escape either.
So like it or not, snart,
with his cold-gun...
Is the only one that can stop them
if Cisco's transportation does not hold.
Then lucky for you,
I figured out what it is you can get me.
Hello, detective. Nice to see you again.
Caitlin, Cisco.
I thought about your proposal.
You want my help...
This is what I want.
My fingerprints, dental records...
DNA, criminal records, family tree.
Everything there is in this world
concerning Leonard snart...
I want it destroyed.
All of it.
At c.C.P.D., online, everywhere.
Joe: The brass on this dude.
You really think we'd do that for you?
If it's the only way, fine.
You and me need to talk right now.
What is wrong with you? You can't
just erase snart's criminal records.
Yeah, I can. And I'll do
whatever I have to do.
- Bar, there's gotta be a different way.
- What is it?
Tell me what it is, and we'll do it.
We're running out of time!
What is going on with you?
You working with that killer?
This isn't who you are.
Who I am is the guy
who's not fast enough to stop Wells.
He hasn't been one step ahead of us, Joe.
He's been a thousand.
I can't catch him. I can't beat him.
What I can do
is save those people down there.
Wells turned them into what they are...
And I'm pretty sure he does not care
if they live or die. I do.
Bye-bye, Leonard snart.
I've deleted everything the c.C.P.D.,
a.R.G.U.S. And the FBI had on you...
And sent a virus to erase
every digital record of you online.
And this is every single piece
of physical evidence the police had.
I hear we're all going
to be working together.
That's right, sis.
Partners.
- Please tell me this is a joke.
- Oh.
You were right, Lenny. She is very uptight.
I am not uptight.
You can't call me uptight.
Look, guys...
We need their help
if we're gonna pull this off.
Why are you wearing your mask?
Snart knows who you are.
And I promised I wouldn't tell anyone.
That includes my sister.
- Jerk.
- Train wreck.
Don't look so surprised, detective.
I am a man of my word.
Yeah, you better be, or I'll make sure
you're on that damn plane too.
Hey, Cisco.
Oh, hey, captain cold's evil sister.
Oh. You're not still mad at me, are you?
I really did enjoy kissing you.
You kissed her?
Under duress. Calm down.
You know, I've thought a lot about you.
Have you really?
Well, stop.
Because this right here...
It ain't gonna happen.
A girl can hope.
Really not enjoying
being one of the good guys this week.
-Really not. Flash: Hey, dude.
Have you figured out a way
to get the metahumans to the airport?
I have, actually.
And it's pretty dope.
This is cool. Where'd you get this?
My uncle owns it. His company hauls
frozen food cross-country.
Okay, so I retrofitted the cooling system
with the wheelchair's power source...
To create an energy damper.
Which means what, exactly?
The back of this rig is being flooded
with so much power...
It's creating a transient pulse strong
enough to disrupt the metahumans' powers.
We can get them to the airport and
on the plane without them getting fresh.
We need somebody with a class a
commercial driver's license to drive this.
I can drive it.
What? I have a class a cdl.
- You do?
- We can't all be doctors.
All right, well, let's do this.
Plane's gonna be here in two hours.
Hey! What the hell?
Hey! Hey!
[Grunting]
Caitlin:
It's done. They're all unconscious.
- The dampers are fully functional.
- Flash: All right.
I'll make sure the roads are clear.
Do not stop for anything.
Let's move out.
After you.
Snart: We got traffic up ahead.
Flash: I'm on it.
Snart: How's our cargo doing?
Cisco: All quiet so far.
Shawna: Don't bother.
Your powers don't work in here.
None of ours do.
- What the hell is going on?
- They're moving us.
- Where?
- Funny, I didn't get an itinerary.
Hey, tall, dark and handsome,
I said your powers are off-line.
All brawn, no brains.
I know you, don't I?
Kyle nimbus.
Used to be a member
of the darbinyan crime family.
- That's right.
- Weren't you executed about a year ago?
-It didn't take. —huh.
Darbinyans weren't known
for hiring the best and brightest.
You couldn't even die right.
So you're so stupid-mad right now, mardon,
you're just gonna pick a fight with anyone?
- Guess so.
- Nimbus: Ifl had my powers right now...
I would gas you all out of existence.
And then you'd be standing in a container
with four corpses.
What would that get you?
Peace and quiet.
I don't know about you guys, but I don't need
my powers to fill this rig full of bodies.
Come on.
[Tires screech]
- What was that?
- Simmons: Wherever they're taking us...
We're here.
Ferris air?
I thought this place got shut down.
It did. One of their
test pilots disappeared.
Where's the plane? I want this over with.
Should be here any minute.
- Look, Joe, I know you don't agree with this...
- Save it, bar. I just wanna get it done.
How come you haven't given me
a code name?
I heard you came up with captain cold.
What do you think I should be called?
Female inmate?
Come on.
You made my gun. Least you
can do is give me a bad-ass alias.
Please?
Fine.
Golden glider.
Smart is sexy, Cisco.
Your a.R.G.U.S. Friends aren't very prompt.
Maybe that's why they've never
been able to catch me.
Oh. There it is.
Turning on each other won't solve anything.
- Nimbus: Don't ever touch me.
- Wait.
[Chuckles]
Vvhoops.
[Computer beeping]
- Uh-oh.
- What's wrong?
That's not good.
Guys.
Guys, we have a problem.
The damper's fluctuating.
The rig's losing power. I don't know why.
- Can you do something?
- Cisco: I'm trying.
Oh, god.
Mardon.
Trip's canceled!
Take your last breath.
[Gunfire]
I'm out of here.
Joe: Caitlin, get down.
[Gunfire]
You locked Ronnie in the pipeline
and you killed Ronnie!
- Caitlin!
- Caitlin: He killed Ronnie!
- What are you doing?
- He killed Ronnie!
[Yells]
Mardon: Finish him, Simmons.
[Groans]
How about we call tonight a tie?
I'd power down if you don't want me
to melt your face.
Let's all go our separate ways.
My name is Leonard snart.
- I know who you are.
- Always pleased to meet a fan.
Just remember who it was made sure
you didn't get thrown on that plane...
Bound for nowhere.
You're just letting us go?
Why'd you shoot that guy?
He owed me money.
Mardon: Hmm.
What? You want a thank-you?
Who doesn't like a thank-you?
Thank you.
Snart: You are so very welcome.
[Groans]
You sabotaged the truck, didn't you?
Why did you let them escape?
Because now they all owe me.
And something tells me they'll be a lot
more use to me as part of my rogues...
Than rotting away in
the north China sea.
You gave me your word.
Heh, heh. It's true, I did. But here's
the thing: I'm a criminal and a liar.
And I hurt people and I Rob them.
What did you expect me to do?
Not be what I am?
I saw an opportunity
to turn things to my advantage...
And I did.
Who you're really mad at is yourself.
This is on you, Barry.
Then why don't you just kill me?
Well, I guess you owe me one now too.
Good luck with all of this.
I'm actually really excited
to see how it all turns out.
[Flash groans]
Hey, hey, hey.
[Engine revs]
Bye, Cisco.
Hey.
Cisco told me you were in here.
How's Caitlin doing?
He used that light
thingy on her. She's fine.
Mostly embarrassed.
Thanks for not saying "I told you so."
But I did tell you so.
Repeatedly.
| just...
Man, I've seen the way
that Oliver does things...
And he's not afraid
to just do whatever it takes...
To get what he needs,
and I thought that I could do that too.
I thought I could just use snart,
but instead he used me.
You're not the arrow, Barry.
That's not the kind of hero you are.
What kind am I?
The kind that cares about whether or not
those criminals lived or died.
I mean, whatever mardon and nimbus
and shawna did, they're human beings...
And you knew letting Wells use them
as pawns was wrong.
You know the difference
between right and wrong.
And you weren't willing to blur the lines
between the two.
That's the kind of man you are.
And that's what makes you different
than the arrow.
So please...
No more walks on the dark side.
[Computer beeping]
- What the hell is that?
- Cisco [over comm]: Guys?
The particle accelerator
is fully charged and online.
Whatever Wells needs it for, it's ready.
- Iris, there really isn't anything else to say.
- Are you kidding me?
You're gonna end this relationship because
some lunatic from the future told you...
That I am destined to marry Barry?
Well, I don't believe that, okay?
I believe that we choose our own destiny.
I decide who I love, and I love you.
Whatever future Wells showed you,
it is not my future.
It's not our future.
Please, let me prove it.
This isn't about the future, Iris.
It's about here...
Now, today.
Ever since the very beginning, there's
been three people in this relationship.
You, me and Barry.
That is not true.
You can deny it all you want,
but Barry knows it...
Joe knows it...
And if I'm gonna be completely honest
with myself...
I knew.
I always knew.
I guess I just thought
I could love you enough to change things.
I'm sorry...
But if you really do love me,
you'll let this end.
Fine.
Then it ends.
Barry, don't even think about it.
Bar, no.
You can't go out there by yourself.
Yeah, I can.
Well, I heard your prison transfer
didn't go so well.
I'm so sorry.
All a part of your plan, I assume.
Actually, that didn't
factor into my plan at all.
But I'm impressed...
You went to such great lengths
to keep those people from harm.
Ever the hero, huh, Barry?
- You've hurt enough people.
- I know. You see me as the villain...
But, Barry, if you were to look back...
Look back carefully
at everything I've done...
Every wheel...
I have set in motion,
you would realize...
I have only done what I had to do.
Nothing more...
Nothing less.
And the particle accelerator?
- How does that fit into your grand plan?
- Why don't you go on inside?
- Let me show you.
- You know, I just learned the hard way...
Not to trust the bad guy.
And yet I've shown you
time and time again...
You can't beat me, Barry.
- Ronnie.
- Firestorm.
Wow. You brought yourself a friend.
Welcome, Mr. Queen.
Hope we're not too late.
You're just in time.
I don't care how fast you are.
You can't fight all three of us
at the same time.
Oh, I can't?
Trust me, this?
This is gonna be fun.
Move, Barry.
[Growls]
Barry, move!
Come on.
Ronnie.
Nanites, courtesy of ray Palmer.
They're delivering a high-frequency pulse
that's disabling your speed.
You're not gonna be running around
for quite a while.
[Both grunting]
Reverse-flash: The history books say
you live to be 86 years old, Mr. Queen.
Well, I guess the history books are wrong.
That's the spirit.
You can't stop me, flash.
And you never will.
[Arrow pierces flesh]
- Thanks, fellas.
- No problem.
Nice haircut.
I see we've abandoned
our traditional green.
Trying something different.
Look, I might need a favor from you.
Wherever, whenever.
I got you.
[English - us - sdh]