Anything?
The intel
I intercepted was clear.
The Wrecking Crew,
at these coordinates.
If they don't show up soon,
we're gonna have an all-out war.
Inside the Avenjet.
Time. To. Smash!
You may have
bested me at this,
but that was
no true victory.
Was that?
Falcon, game of darts?
Arrows versus...
Whatever those things
are you shoot.
Flechettes.
I'm finishing up this
electromagnetic particle gun.
"Electromagmata,"
what, now?
It works by magnetically
combining the electron fields
of an ionized...
Oh, I'm sorry. I fell asleep while you
were talking nerd stuff.
We've got visual.
So much for that awesome gear
you promised, Wrecker.
-You got played!
-Wrong.
A.I.M.'s abandoned tech.
-Time for the Wrecking Crew to upgrade.
-Yeah!
-Avengers...
-Smash!
I don't think that's where Cap
was going with that, Hulk.
Tired of waiting.
You think tech will make
you guys better?
Please.
You'll always be a wreck.
It's your name!
Sorry, guys.
Emergency exit only.
Who's the wreck now?
Is this a trick question?
So far, not a big fan
of the Wrecking Crew's upgrade.
Huh?
Hope this doesn't bore you
again, Hawkeye!
Oh, and this? This is my molecular
restraint system.
Nerd stuff.
More fun than thumb wrestling.
Outthinking the enemy
is the first step to outfighting them.
Couldn't have done it
better myself.
Okay. I could have, but...
I'm still impressed.
Nothing to say?
Falcon's tech did save
your quiver, after all.
Sure. Yeah. Thanks.
You seem to have
your arrows in a knot.
Was saving you the wrong
thing to do or something?
I appreciate the save,
but anyone with that gun
could have done the same thing.
A real hero has skills!
My tech is my skill.
You think anyone could
just put on this suit and be Falcon?
No, not anyone.
Hulk's way too heavy.
He'd never get airborne.
Hey!
-A little off?
-Thanks to you.
Don't ruin my concentration.
I'm busy.
Some of us need to keep
our skills sharp.
I think I can help
with that.
-Not interested.
-Check it.
Never-miss arrows.
Can I borrow that?
Load it into the bow,
like normal.
State your target,
then shoot.
Hulk's sandwich!
Target confirmed.
Hey!
See? Works every time.
Just another toy.
That never misses!
There's more to me than
just hitting targets.
You could give those arrows
to everyone on the team,
and they still
wouldn't be Hawkeye.
-Center target.
-Target confirmed.
Any more
brilliant inventions?
One of you is toast!
Never mind.
An electronic shield
that calculates its own flight path.
Target confirmed.
Bet Cap
won't be too impressed.
Energy gloves.
Now Hulk's not the only one
with smashing power.
Trying to mimic
everyone else's powers?
You're just
proving my point.
Okay. What about this?
An Asgardian Runestone.
I'm trying to recreate
Thor's powers.
You just twist this, and...
According to my calculations,
it should do something
like this...
I guess.
What did you just do?
I'm betting you didn't
transport us to Jersey.
Got it under control.
I'll just reverse...
Oh, great. The other half
must still be in the tower.
You're right.
This sure isn't Jersey.
I got this!
Huh?
My suit. It's shorted out!
All my gear!
That creature
shorted it out.
I don't think we're going to find you
an electrical outlet here.
You strangers dare come to Vanaheim
with electric machines?
Whoa, whoa, whoa.
We didn't dare anything.
Genius here accidentally
teleported us from Earth to...
Where'd you say?
Vanaheim?
Does that happen
to be in Jersey?
All right, look. I'm Falcon,
and this charming guy
is Hawkeye.
And what's wrong
with our electricity?
Them. The Shadow Nixes
feed off of it.
Our realm has
banished such things.
Oh, you are gonna
love it here.
The Shadow Nixes have grown more
bold since the Great Light burned out.
And I was unable to find
more potion to fuel it.
Wasn't she speaking English
just a second ago?
Wait, "potion"?
"Great Light"?
So, you don't have technology,
you have...
Magic.
Hurry! We have no time!
No tech. Magic!
-I've never felt more useless.
-I got a use for you.
Figure out how to get us
out of the Hundred Acre Wood,
and back to New York with all its
glorious streetlights and power sockets.
Not without the rest
of the Runestone.
Someone back at the tower
has to fire it up to bring us back.
Great! This trip keeps
getting better and better.
Oh, no! My village!
One, two, three!
You must declare me
Master of the Wrestling
of Thumbs.
Never!
The winner of the next round
takes on both
of the newcomers.
Uh, no, thanks. I'm actually
going horseback riding.
The police let me ride
with their horse trainer.
-Anyone want to come along?
-Do I look like I ride horses?
-Huh?
-So much for a day off.
Who invited these things?
Hey.
I do the smashing
around here!
Incoming!
Looks like they
drain electricity!
Of course they do!
They're Shadow Nixes from Vanaheim!
More intel, please.
What's a Shadow Nix?
Mystical creatures
that feed on electricity.
How these two got here,
I've no idea.
If we don't stop them,
they'll send Earth into the Stone Age.
Magic isn't real, Thor.
I'm not buyin' it!
I'd say you just bought it.
No tech?
Let's do this old school!
Neat trick!
Got anything else?
Still... Not... Impressed.
We have to herd these
creatures back to Vanaheim.
I should really start
carrying a can opener with me.
Very funny.
You stop those Nixes,
and I'm gonna figure out
how our power-hungry friends
got here in the first place.
-Excuse us. Pardon me.
-Out of my way. Watch your back
Coming through.
My village can't stop them
without the Great Light!
Who needs a "Great Light"
when you've got all this stuff and me?
I'm starting
to like this place!
-Whoa.
-Just usin' my skills, Falcon.
I've never seen our weapons
used that way.
You're not the only one
with skills!
Get these villagers inside!
I got this!
Lady Freya. The potion!
There is none, Elder Lorak.
My mission was a failure.
Then we truly are doomed.
What exactly is this
"Great Light"?
It's been lit for centuries,
keeping the Shadow Nixes at bay.
It has never
gone out before.
And you can't re-light it
without this magic potion?
I need some more data.
Information. Anything
you have on the Great Light.
These are the spells
that illuminate it,
but this language is ancient,
and none of us
can understand it.
Close the gates!
You're about to have some
unwanted house guests!
Please tell me your village
has an escape tunnel or something?
The Nixes will not stop
with the village!
Without the Great Light,
-they will take over this entire realm!
-Hmm.
Jarvis, can you hear me?
And of course not.
No power, no Jarvis.
Hawkeye! Falcon! You guys
taking a vacation or something?
Now, where did those
two uglies come from?
For creatures that feed on power,
New York is a glorious feast!
Hey, I was watchin' that!
Here's Hulk in your eye!
Where are ya?
Watch your step, ma'am.
Fun!
And don't come back!
You're not that scary, Hulk.
They're going after something.
I am too that scary.
They're headed
for the power plant.
First Jersey, then the world.
If the Nixes reach their
upper limit of power,
they will be unstoppable.
Centuries ago, they nearly
wiped Vanaheim from the Nine Realms.
Their appetite is voracious.
Know the feeling.
Move, move, move!
Huh. Nothing like
a little improvisation.
Why does your partner
not help?
Falcon? Not much
he can do without tech.
He's probably taking a nap.
-Will these do?
-Awesome!
I still need three ounces
of calcium carbonate.
I mean, grab me
a chunk of limestone.
Now, if I were the key to sending
energy-hungry creatures
back to an Asgardian realm,
where would I be?
What do I always say about
playing with Thor's toys?
Don't these things
ever get tired?
Come on!
That was brand new!
Falcon?
You got your net arrows,
some flame arrows...
Oh and be careful
with the goo arrows.
Stickiest tree sap
I've ever seen.
Wait. You made all this?
-Just usin' my skills, Hawkeye.
-Touche.
Of course you know
how to ride a horse.
I didn't spend a month training with
the cavalry for nothing.
Looks like Falcon and Hawkeye
broke a Runestone
from Asgard.
I'm guessing it switched them
with these Nixes
from Vanaheim.
Can you Pony Express
this thing?
Snowball's not a pony.
He's a stallion.
Hey! Big guy!
Yeah, you!
Over here! Yeah!
Bring your friends, too!
Uh, I never voted
for this plan.
Your turn, kids!
Just like we practiced!
Just a little sulfur
compound I whipped up. Ugh!
Kids love it.
Thor! Hawkeye and Falcon brought
these things here with your Runestone.
Can you reverse it?
Aye! And I clearly need
to lock the door to my quarters.
All the gooey arrows in the world
aren't going to replace that Great Light.
Right. Should be ready.
Wait. You managed
to master magic, too?
Magic's just technology
we don't understand.
The potion's
a chemical solution.
I took ten parts magnesium
and let it...
Wait.
Nerd stuff.
I don't want to bore you.
No, not bored, just...
Way over my head.
They've activated
the Runestone from Earth!
Perfect timing as always.
-A little teamwork?
-I like your thinking.
The Great Light
burns once again!
Thank you, heroes.
Let us always remember
in myth, legend and song
the great Falcon and his
trusty sidekick, Hawkeye!
Yeah.
Wait, wait, wait. What?
Now we really are in Jersey?
It failed to
transport them back!
The Shadow Nixes have
grown too powerful!
Any bright ideas,
hero of Vanaheim?
Yes! Literally.
Thor!
How did you obtain
a Great Light?
Long story. I need
some amplification.
Skills.
Let's see how hungry you are
for the power of the Nine Realms!
On it!
Twelve o'clock! Heads up!
Watch your back!
On your right!
On your left!
-Well-played.
-Workin' on my skills.
Getting caught in Vanaheim
without my gear was a wakeup call.
I couldn't have been
more wrong.
I thought your strength
was only in your tech.
But your tech just
shows your real skill,
recognizing
and solving problems.
Which is kind of heroic,
right?
Heads up!
From you, that's high praise.
Yeah.
Don't get used to it.